University of Connecticut
© 2010 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, Athletic Game Films Collection.
undated, circa 1930-1998.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut. Division of Athletics.
40 linear feet.
The collection contains moving image recordings (in multiple formats) of University athletic games throughout the 20th century.
MSS19970012
History
The University of Connecticut Division of Athletics oversees and organizes both men's and woman's sports.
Scope and Content
The collection contains approxomately seversl hundred reels of 16mm film, VHS video and betacam tapes that document some of the intercollegiate competitions of the University of Connecticut's football, basketball, soccer, tennis, archery, and track teams which date from circa 1930-1998. Many of the games were filmed and developed by Jerauld A. Manter, a UConn faculty member.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by format and chronologically therein.
Series I: 16mm film ( undated, 1944-1979 )
Series II: VHS tape ( undated, 1986-1998 )
Series III: Other formats ( undated, 1986-2000 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff, and students. Realted materaisl may also be found in the sport media guides (Dodd periodicals) and programs and in the Athletic Communications Office Records. For detailed information about this collection please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Organizations:
University of Connecticut.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Document Types:
Videocassettes.; Audio visual materials.; Motion picture film.
Restrictions on Access
Access to media is by appointment only.
Acquisition Information
Materials in the collection have been transfered to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center from the Division of Athletics periodically beginning in the mid 1980s.
Detailed Description
- Series I: 16mm film, undated, 1941-1979
  - Football, undated
  - vs. Hofstra University, undated
  - Football, 1941-1948
  - vs. New York University, 1944 January 8
  - vs. New York University, 1946 December 7
  - vs. Yale University, 1947 February 19
  - vs. New York University, 1947 December 16
  - Football, 1949-1951
  - vs. University of New Hampshire, 1949 January 18
  - vs. Springfield College, 1950 December
  - vs. Boston College, 1950
  - Football, 1952-1956
  - vs. Brown University, 1952
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1952 February 23
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1954 February 27
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1955 February
  - vs. St. Louis University, 1955 March 12
  - vs. Manhattan College, 1955 December
  - Football, 1957-1966
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1957 January
  - vs. Syracuse University, 1957 January
  - vs. University of Massachusetts, 1957 February
  - vs. Temple University, 1958 December 27
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1958 January 11
  - vs. Dartmouth College, 1958 March 11
  - vs. Yale University, 1959 December 5
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1959 January 10
  - vs. University of Maine, 1961 February 11
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1961 January 14
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1961 February 18
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1962 March 3
  - Season Highlights, 1961-1962
  - vs. University of New Hampshire, 1964 January 11
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1964 February 15
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1964 January 1
  - vs. American International College, 1964 December 1
  - vs. Harvard University, 1964 December 9
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1965 January 5
  - vs. University of New Hampshire, 1965 February 27
  - Football, 1966
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1966 January 15
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1966 March 1
  - Football, 1967
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1967 January 14
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1967 March 1
  - vs. University of Massachusetts, 1967 February 1
  - vs. University of Maine, 1967 February 4
  - Football, 1967-1968
  - Football, 1968-1969
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1968 February 22
  - vs. University of Massachusetts, 1968 January 31
  - vs. University of New Hampshire, 1968 January 10
  - vs. University of New Hampshire, 1968 January 10
  - vs. University of Massachusetts, 1968 December 1
  - Football, 1969
  - vs. Syracuse University, 1969 January 8
  - Season Highlights, 1968-1969
  - vs. University of New Hampshire, 1969-1970
  - Football, 1969-1970
  - Football, 1970
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1970
  - Football, 1970-1971
  - vs. Boston College, 1970-1971
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1971-1972
  - Football (2), 1971
  - Football, 1972
  - Football, 1972-1973
  - vs. Boston College, 1973 February 27
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1973 January 20
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1973 February 20
  - Football, 1973-1974
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1974 February 5
  - vs. St. John's University, 1973-1974
  - vs. Boston College, 1974-1975
  - vs. Boston University, 1974 January 22
  - vs. Rutgers University, 1975 February 11
  - vs. University of Massachusetts, 1975 February 15
  - vs. Boston College, 1975 January 2
  - Football, 1975-1976
  - vs. Manhattan College, 1975-1976
  - vs. University of Massachusetts, 1975-1976
  - vs. University of New Hampshire, 1975-1976
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1975-1976
  - Football, 1975-1977
  - Football, 1976
  - vs. Rutgers University, 1976 March 18
  - vs. University of Rhode Island, 1976-1977
  - vs. Duke University, 1976-1977
  - Football, 1976-1978
  - vs. Fairfield University, 1977 March 1
  - vs. Manhattan College, 1977-1978
  - vs. Fordham University, 1977-1978
  - vs. University of Massachusetts, 1977-1978
  - Football, 1977-1978
  - vs. Syracuse University, 1978-1979
  - vs. East Carolina University, 1978 December 30
  - Football, 1978-1980
  - vs. College of the Holy Cross, 1979 January 26
  - Football, 1980-1981
  - Football, 1982-1983
- Series II: VHS tape, undated, 1986-
  - vs. University of Pittsburgh, undated (January 6)
  - vs. Boston University, 1986 December 9
  - vs. Yale University, 1987
  - vs. St. John's University, 1987 February 18
  - vs. Syracuse Unviersity, 1987 February 7
  - University of Pittsburgh vs. Georgetown University, 1988 January 11
  - vs. Yale University, 1988 November 30
  - vs. Syracuse University, 1988 February 20
  - vs. Providence College, 1988 February 8
  - vs. Providence College, 1988 January 9
  - vs. University of West Virginia, 1988 March 17
  - vs. Virginia Commonwealth University, 1988 March 25
  - NIT Semi-Finals, 1988 March 30
  - vs. University of North Carolina at Charlotte, 1989 March 15
  - vs. Unviersity of Pittsburgh, 1989 February 25
  - vs. Georgetown University, 1989 January 21
  - vs. Seton Hall University, 1989 February 8
  - vs. Boston College, 1989 February 22
  - vs. Texas A & M Unviersity, 1989 November 24
  - vs. Villanova University, 1989 January 4
  - vs. Villanova University, 1989 December 12
  - vs. Seton Hall University, 1990 February 24
  - vs. St. John's University, 1990 January 27
  - Georgetown University vs. Providence College, 1990 February 13
  - Villanova University vs. Syracuse University, 1990 February 12
  - Providence College vs. St. John's University, 1990 February 17
  - vs. Villanova University, 1990 January 9
  - vs. Seton Hall University, 1990 March 9
  - vs. Georgetown University, 1990 March 10
  - vs. Providence College, 1990 February 19
  - vs. Seton Hall University, 1990 January 13
  - vs. University of Massachusetts, 1990 January 30
  - vs. Syracuse University, 1990 March 11
  - vs. University of New Hampshire, 1990 December 12
  - vs. Georgetown University, 1990 January 20
  - vs. Duke University, 1991 March 22
  - vs. University of Pittsburgh, 1991 March 2
  - Georgetown University vs. Syracuse University, 1991 March 3
  - vs. University of Pittsburgh, 1991 February 13
  - vs. St. John's University, 1991 January 7
  - vs. Villanova University, 1992 January 11
  - vs. University of Miami, 1992 January 2
  - vs. University of Miami, 1992 January 18
  - vs. University of Pittsburgh, 1992 January 14
  - vs. Syracuse University, 1992 February 3
  - vs. St. John's University, 1992 February 1
  - vs. St. John's University, 1992 March 13
  - vs. Villanova University, 1992 January 27
  - vs. Seton Hall University, 1993 January 4
  - vs. Central Connecticut Stae University, 1993 December 11
  - vs. Syracuse University, 1994 January 10
  - vs. Syracuse University, 1995 January 23
  - vs. University of Notre Dame, 1996 November 11
  - vs. St. John's University, 1998 November 1
  - Men's Basketball Promotional, 1998 February 7
- Series III: Other formats, undated, 1986-2000
  - vs. Old Dominion University (U-Matic), undated
  - vs. Louisiana Tech University (U-Matic), undated
  - MELT Reel #2 vs. Fairfield University/University of Notre Dame/George Washington University, undated
  - vs. Rutgers University, undated
  - vs. Lehigh University, 1986
  - vs. Syracuse University (U-Matic), 1987 January 3
  - vs. Yale University (U-Matic), 1987 December 2
  - vs. University of Hartford (U-Matic), 1987 December 28
  - vs. Princeton University (U-Matic), 1987 December 29
  - vs. Fairfield University (U-Matic), 1988 February 18
  - vs. Boston College (U-Matic; Highlights), 1988 February 5
  - vs. St. John's University (U-Matic), 1988 January 23
  - vs. Seton Hall University (U-Matic), 1988 January 5
  - vs. Boston College (U-Matic), 1988 February 23
  - vs. University of Pittsburgh (U-Matic), 1988 January 13
  - vs. Providence College (U-Matic), 1988 February 8
  - vs. Pepperdine University (U-Matic), 1988 January 2
  - vs. Boston College (U-Matic; NIT), 1988
  - vs. Louisiana Tech University (U-Matic), 1988
  - vs. University of West Virginia (U-Matic), 1988 March 17
  - vs. Virginia Commonwealth University (U-Matic), 1988 March 25
  - vs. Ohio State University (U-Matic), 1988
  - vs. Boston University (U-Matic/Beta [Large]), 1990 March 15
  - vs. University of California (Beta [Large]/Reel-to-Reel), 1990 March 17
  - vs. Providence College (U-Matic), 1990 January 21
  - vs. Furman University (Beta [Small]), 1991 December 28
  - vs. Providence College (Beta [Small]), 1992 January 22
  - vs. Boston College (Beta [Small]), 1994 January 8
  - vs. Boston College (Beta [Large]), 1994 December 6
  - vs. University of Tennesse-Chattanooga (Beta [Small & Large formats]), 1995 March 16
  - vs. UIniversity of Cincinnati(Beta [Small & Large formats]), 1995 March 18
  - vs. University of Miami (Beta [Large]), 1995 January 31
  - vs. University of Maryland (Beta [Large]), 1995 March 23
  - vs. University of California at Los Angeles (Beta [Large]), 1995 March 25
  - NCAA 1st Round MELT (Beta [Large]; Reel 1), 1995 March 16
  - Regional Semifinals (Beta [Large]), 1995 March 25
  - Men's Basketball Promotional (Beta [Small]), 1998 February 7
  - vs. University of Pittsburgh (Beta [Large]), 1999 January 31
  - vs. University of Arizona (Beta [Small]), 2000 December 9